

# I AM JAMES FINLEY

I am **James Finley**. Yeah, Finley as in a descendant of **MacBeth**, King of Scotland. I am a **software engineer** with over **20 years of experience** in JavaScript, CSS, PHP, mySQL, and even Swift on iOS.

My passion lies in crafting **accessible**, **user-friendly**, and **lightning-fast experiences**. Throughout my career, I've woven a rich tapestry of successful projects, each contributing to a legacy of excellence.

james@finleyho.me

# **EXPERIENCE**

### **WWT** - Lead UX Frontend Engineer

Over the span of five years, I led dynamic teams in delivering innovative solutions for clients across diverse sectors, including banking, communications, utilities, education, and medical technologies. My expertise lies in leveraging modern frontend frameworks such as React and Angular, along with CMS software like Craft CMS. My unwavering focus on user experience ensures lightning-fast interfaces, highly accessible applications, and delightful interactions with every tap.

**Skills used:** React, Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript, PHP, mySQL, Craft CMS, UX, interface design

August 2018 — February 2024

# Intercard - iOS Engineer

I joined the team to create cross-platform mobile apps that handle card balances for arcades and gaming businesses. Along the way, I also got involved in the building of a web app for making reservations for parties and events, while mentoring a young developer that was on the project.

Skills used: Swift, C#, Xamarin, Angular 4, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

August 2017 — August 2018

## **Emerson Climate Technologies** - Front-End Web Developer

At Emerson, I spearheaded the development of polished user experiences across various products, including ComfortGuard and Sensi. I also designed mobile-friendly email notifications. Additionally, I crafted a visually appealing marketing website for Sensi using Craft CMS. This website streamlined access to answers for common questions, highlighted new and upcoming features, and facilitated the purchase and installation of the Sensi thermostat.

Skills used: HTML, CSS, PHP, Salesforce, JavaScript, Node.js, Craft CMS

March 2016 - June 2017

### **HLK** - Front-End Web Developer

I built and maintained WordPress sites for clients, including Monsanto.

**Skills used:** WordPress, Responsive Web Design, PHP, mySQL, HTML, Sass/CSS, JavaScript, Objective-C

July 2015 — January 2016

### eTecc / Interactive - Software Engineer

While at eTecc, I built large-scale PHP/mySQL applications for car dealership industry and white-label iOS apps for dealership customers, deploying over a dozen apps for Ford, Mazda, Nissan, and more. These apps allowed for insurance claims to be filed by customers and managed by employees.

**Skills used:** Responsive Web Design, PHP, mySQL, HTML, Sass/CSS, design, Objective-C *July* 2013 – *July* 2015

## higi - Front-End Developer

I helped the redevelopment of higi's marketing site to support mobile devices with responsive web development techniques and worked with the team to conceive, plan, and build new features for their web app using PHP, mySQL, and modern web standards.

**Skills used:** Responsive Web Design, PHP, mySQL, HTML, Sass/CSS, jQuery, design September 2012 – June 2013

### Echo Design Group - Senior Web Developer

Joining the team right as the whole Responsive Web Design movement kicked off, I built a dozen sites from start to launch, working with the design team to implement strong, mobile-friendly experiences. I also helped them improve their organizational workflow, including utilizing Github for deployment and version control and built a custom CMS for managing web sites.

**Skills used:** Responsive Web Design, PHP, mySQL, HTML, Sass/CSS, jQuery, design July 2011 – August 2012

## Abt - Developer

Managed multiple projects and worked with the team to better organize projects and communication.

Skills used: PHP, mySQL, HTML, CSS, jQuery, design January 2011 – June 2011

# Community Christian Church - Web Development Director

I built a new web application that brought a brand new view of social interactivity to church websites and also brought a full online church system for running both live and prerecorded services. I honed my skills in asynchronous JavaScript, Flash, PHP and relational databases.

**Skills used:** PHP, Code Igniter, mySQL, HTML, CSS, jQuery, ActionScript 3.0, design and layout

December 2009 - January 2011

## Clear Channel Radio - Senior Online Content Manager

I led the development of an application for managing the office paperwork that covered everything from the sale of an ad to a client to the production and airing of the ad on the radio. Not only this, but I was also largely in charge of the websites for two radio stations in Chicago.

**Skills used:** PHP, Code Igniter, mySQL, HTML, CSS, jQuery, ActionScript 3.0, design and layout

 $September\ 2008-May\ 2009$ 

# **EDUCATION**

# The Illinois Institute of Art - Schaumburg

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Web Design & Interactive Media

December 2008